Meng Vang

Maplewood, MN 55119

(651) 724-5156 ~ meng.vang92@yahoo.com Portfolio ~ mvang92.github.io/Portfolio/

Software Engineer

Software Engineer intern with experience to front/back-end technologies along with writing automation tests. Fast learner, self-driven worker, and a team player with the aptitude to take on new challenges. Skilled at writing documentation and efficient code using best practices in software engineering.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML (CSS), Java, Kotlin, Python, PHP

Technologies: TestNG, Express, React, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Angular, Node, NPM, AJAX, API, JSON

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Amazon RedShift, Firebase

Software: IntelliJ, VS Code, GitHub, BitBucket, Robo 3T, MySQL Workbench, Microsoft Office Suite

Scrum Tools: Jira, Confluence

Certifications

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities

October 2018

Full-Stack Web Development

Education

University of Wisconsin – River Falls (AACSB)

May 2015

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science and Information Systems

Work Experience

Virgin Pulse April 2019 – Present

Software Engineering Intern – Platform Excellence (PLEX) Team

- Working closely with Scrum and development teams to investigate and resolve client escalated issues
- Write automation tests with SDET team using TestNG to prevent errors that may occur for the user
- Troubleshoot failing tests by diagnosing the issue and making necessary changes to resolve them
- Participate in code reviews by suggesting changes to maintain consistency with approved design
- · Contribute to writing and updating documentation in Confluence to keep up with current technology
- Train a number of newly hired interns and Associate Software Engineers to understand our platform

Freelance Software Developer

CarSpace October 2018 – Present

- This full-stack application allows car enthusiasts to keep track of their vehicle maintenance history.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Express Server, React, Node, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Firebase

Diet Matador January 2019 – Present

- This full-stack application promotes healthy eating and provides nutritional facts about common foods.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Express Server, React, Node, JavaScript, Tailwind, Firebase

JavaDB December 2018 – Present

- This simple application connects to an SQL server to perform various CRUD operations.
- Technologies: Java, SQL

Allina Health / Abbott Northwestern Hospital

October 2018 – March 2019

IT Consultant

- Improved workflow and efficiency by using Microsoft Access (SQL) and Excel to modify databases
- Supported management and peers in deploying software upgrades during Windows 10 migration